there's been a lot of discussion about
meaning in life but I think the best
discussion of it is by Susan wolf in her
book meaning in life and why it matters
right and she she boils it down to this
very interest she goes through lots of
things and she gives a lot of argument
how it's not reducible to morality how
it's not reducible to sort of material
success I invite you to read those I
can't go I don't have time to go through
those right now right and she says it
comes down to what initially what people
say they want to be connected to
something bigger than themselves but
then she says that's just a metaphor
it's not like you know if I chained you
to a mountain you're happy right there's
a metaphor here she says what it is is
we want to be right creatively
participating in something that has a
value independent of our valuing of it
she has a formula for that she says we
want subjective attraction to meet
objective attractiveness and then she
hits a naturalistic roadblock and the
book sort of goes a little because she
says the problem is there's no such
thing
things don't intrinsically have a value
things don't objectively have a value so
what are we gonna do and she done she
she considers one answer that people
have well what we do is we value what
other people value and she says that's
not quite right you know you've got bill
he knows that lots of people care about
the maple leaves so he devotes his whole
life to you know thinking and talking
about the maple leafs we're not
convinced bill's leading a good life
right and that's where she sort of stops
I want to try and go a little bit
farther right I want to try and go a
little bit further and say what we want
is we want to be connected to something
that we find profound and that we take
very seriously and that something and
that something towards which we can have
reverence